Mark Lam

1770 Dean Street Brooklyn, New York USA +1 661 478 9651

mark@markofthelam.com

markofthelam.com github.com/emceelamb

I'm a sculptor and media scholar turned developer with over five years experience developing websites and digital design for businesses ranging from e-commerce to independent artists. Most recently I have been working towards a Master's degree at New York University where I research interactive media making using computer networking technology. Some of my other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and making generative sound objects.

Areas of Interest

- Computer Networking for Expressive Media
- Interactive Interfaces
- Real-time Data Visualization
- Empathetic Conceptual Development

Education

2020 Interactive Telecommunications, Master of Professional Studies

New York University, New York City

2015 Media Studies & Art Practice, Bachelor of Arts

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

Graphic Design, Associate of Arts

College of the Canyons, Valencia

Previous Experience

2015-ongoing

2013

Self-employed Freelance Developer NYC, HCMC, LA, Berkeley

- Design and develop websites for business ranging from personal artist to independent publishing houses
- · Research and advise clients on web features including image api's to online payment procedure
- Scope timelines and specifications while coordinating with clients to meet objectives

2018–2019 LINCOLN CENTER FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS

Digital Accessibility Fellow

New York City

- Audit internal and external digital media of a world-class performing arts institution and write recommandations to meet WCAG 2.1 compliance
- · Create internal digital accessibility training material to promote access for a diverse customer base
- · Develop a fully compliant digital map of campus accessibility features to allow for increased physical access
- · Create work process for captioning a catalog of over 1000 hours of video content to bring media to digital compliance

2018–2020 New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer

New York City

- · Develop and test an internal resource site for New York University's ITP program
- · Work directly with faculty and staff to scope information priorities
- · Implement WAI-ARIA features to meet WCAG 2.1 compliance and university wide accessibility initiative

2017–2018 Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology & Education

Visiting Lecturer - Introductory Programming, English

Ho Chi Minh City

- · Develop an introductory English/programming curriculum in the C language for non-native English speaking students
- $\bullet \ \ Lead \ supplemental \ workshops \ in \ specialized \ programming \ topics \ such \ as \ web \ design \ and \ portfolio \ building$
- Collaborate with student leaders to promote extracurricular English study

Projects & Workshops

2020 Automating Mindfully, Technical Workshop

Unconference at ITP NYU, New York City

- Introduction to Bash scripting
- · Explore mindfulness and technology

2019 Network Operator, Performance

2019

NIME 2019, New York City

- · Explore computer networking technology as medium for musical expression
- Live network programming

Lincoln Center Campus Accessibility Map, Digital Map

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, New York City

- Create an accessible digital map of the Lincoln Center Campus
- Extend Google Maps API to incorporate WAI-ARIA features